BRIAN THOMAS

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Summary

Hey! I'm Brian, a Front End developer in the DFW area with a knack for programming, solving problems and creating great/responsive applications.

Skills

FRONT-END: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+, ¡Query

BACK-END: Node.js, express

FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES/PREPROCESSORS: React / Redux, Boostrap, Foundation, Materialize, SASS/SCSS, Express, Material-UI, Redux, Redux, Redux, Redux, Redux

CMS: Wordpress, Kentico, SiteFinity

SOURCE CONTROL: Git, GitHub, BitBucket, GitLab

DEPLOYMENT: Heroku, Firebase, Netlify

TESTING: Mocha/Chai, Jest

SEO: Google Tag Manager, Google Analytics **MOBILE APP DEVELOPMENT:** React-Native

Projects

Trinity Consultants

I was the sole Front End Developer of a complete website rebuild/redesign. Keeping there current Ucommerce mission in mind, my goal was to create a better user experience, cleaner design while using mobile first approach. Across the project I worked with multiple API's, frameworks and several third party intergrations (Stripe, SiteFinity(CMS))

Tech used: JS, SASS/SCSS, React, SEO, Stripe API, Google Maps API. JSON/AJAX

MedpropertiesLP

As the lead Front End Developer, I worked on a complete redesign, keeping there mission of simple but yet coming across as modern.

Tech used: HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, Wordpress

Ultra Agency

Created a dummy Front-End Agency site called Ultra, showing the different models while sticking with a simplistic, clean, modern approach. Mobile Responsive **Tech used**: React, React-Router-DOM, Style-Components, Materialize, Netlify

Apple Store

Apple Store E-Commerce platform built with the MERN stack & Redux.

Tech used: SASS, React, Axios, Redux, Node.js, Express, Heroku

Employment

Imaginuity

Dallas,TX

Software Developer

Mar. 2019 - Current

- $\ensuremath{\mathsf{Developed}}$ multiple/new high customer traffic websites and applications.
- Maintained numerous customer sites to stay up to date with the latest practices and clients needs.
- Successfully identified, diagnosed, and fixed websites/application problems, including some issues like formatting issues, logic features, broken links and more.
- Helped to achieve a consistent look and visual theme across the website by formatting, images and layout.
- Evaluated and became knowledgeable in new standards, technologies and certain CMS (Wordpress, Kentico).

Front End Freelancer

2018 - 2019

Verizon

Technical Sales

Frisco,TX Aug. 2015 - Feb. 2019

Contact

brianthomas571@gmail.com

www.brianthomas.io/

\$ 972-804-2000

♀ Plano.TX

in brian-thomas-132350146/

Bjthomas11

Education

THINKFUL / FULL STACK FLEX PROGRAM

Aug. 2018 - Feb. 2019

2011

Graduated February 2019

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Redux, and algorithms, data structures. Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating with a senior developer every week.

COLLIN COMMUNITY COLLEGE 2015 - 2018

TEXAS TECH UNIVERSITY 2012 - 2014

PLANO SR. HIGH SCHOOL High School Degree 2011